Nattell, Tom; Papers apap191
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Subject Files for research, 1967-1998; Undated; 4; 2.25 cubic ft.
  This series contains research conducted by Nattell. This series reflects his non-occupational or educational research. He utilized some of the research in his articles or in preparation for events. Included are magazines, newsletters, promotional material, notes, press releases, stickers and ephemera, correspondence, reports, and maps. Topics covered in this series include the Watervliet Arsenal, the Coalition to Keep Albany's Name Nuclear Free protest against the USS Albany, home gardening advice, Capital District evacuation plans and more.
  - AIDS: reports, articles, news clippings, press releases, notes, 1989 June 12-1998 December 01 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 14)
  - Amnesty International: newsletters containing articles by Nattell, 1988/1989 Winter; 1998 Summer; 1998 Autumn (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 15)
  - Anti-Nuclear War: articles, news clippings, boycott forms, 1983 October 16-1989 Fall; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 16)
  - Art and Ephemera: proofs, stickers, art, Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 17)
  - Asbestos: EPA documents, 1979 March; 1979 April; 1980 April (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 18)
  - Assorted Magazines, 1979 April 13-1980 June (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 19-20)
  - Assorted Newspapers and Newsletters, 1980 Spring-1991 Fall (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 21)
  - Assorted topics: pamphlet, news clippings, fliers, correspondence, source book, presentation transcripts, 1979 April 06-1984 October; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 22)
  - Banned Book Week: articles and correspondence confirming Nattell's reading, 1991 September 20; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 23)
  - British Armament: News clippings, notes, 1983 September 16-1983 November 27; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 24)
  - Bureau of Indian Affairs Services to Natives information documents, 1977 November-1978 April (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 25)
  - Capital District Risk Areas: evacuation instructions, notes, Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 26)
  - Civil Defense Alternatives: correspondence, press releases, resolutions, news clipping, 1982 November 23-1983 February 27; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 27)
  - Civil Defense documents and correspondence, news clippings, Grand Zero task inform, 1981 February 27-1982 February 01 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 28)
  - Chernobyl: news clippings, articles, talking prints, 1986 May 12-1988 December (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 29)
  - Children and Nuclear war: press releases, articles, news clippings, 1984 April; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 30)
  - Coalition for a Clean Mohawk River: press releases, news releases, correspondence, radioactivity report, 1983 November 15-1990 March 08; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 31)
  - Coalition for Direct Action at Seabrook: press releases, pamphlets, bumper sticker, notes, correspondence, 1979 April 26; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 32)
  - Coalition for Nature Rights and survival: letterhead, Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 33)
  - Coalition to Keep Albany's Name Nuclear Free: clippings, map, script, 1986 December 23-1990 May 20; Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 10)
  - Coalition to Keep Albany's Name Nuclear-Free: press releases, correspondence, news clippings, protest coordination, 1986 August 26-1990 June 12; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 34-35)
  - Concerned Citizens for the Environment: press releases and letter, 1989 May 04; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 36)
  - Draft Registration: news clippings, 1980 June 17; 1980 July 04; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 37)
  - Energy: notes, articles, poem, pamphlets, research materials, 1977 April; 1977 June; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 38)
  - Energy and War: article, job applications, correspondence, 1977; 1981 April 10; 1981 September 02; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 39)
  - "Energy Conservation: Emerging consensus, Diverging Commitment" by Joint Congressional Committee "The potential for Fuel conservation" by Mark H. Ross and Robert H. Williams, 1977 February; 1981 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 40)
  - "The Economic and Social Status of the American Indian, 1940-1970" article by Alan L. Sorkin, Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 41)
  - The Farm: map, newsletter, report, 1981 Winter/Spring; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 42)
  - Federal Budget: Task Force report, news clippings, status reports, 1982 April 01; 1982 November 22; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 43)
  - Friends of the Earth: newsletter for New York branch, 1982 Spring (Box 5 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 44)
  - Gardening: news clippings, pamphlets, maps of gardens and notes, newsletters, 1975 October-1982 August 08; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 1)
  - Gina: "El Extreme" 33 1/3 RPM record, 1992 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 2)
  - Global Warming: pamphlets, notes, papers, 1984 February 24; 1989 September; 1990 September 11; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 3)
  - Ground Zero Week: articles, forms, newsletters, fliers, 1982 January 01-1983 March 01; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 4)
  - Ground Zero: press packet with photos, 1988 June 08 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 5)
  - Hiroshima and Nagasaki: newspaper clippings, 1985 July 16; 1985 August 04; 1986 August 07; 1987 February 12; 1987 November 25 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 6)
  - "How to Map the effects of a Nuclear Attack in your community" article, Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 7)
  - Hydro:Quebec: correspondence, impact reviews, letter draft, 1991 October 23; 1991 November 14; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 8)
  - Information pamphlets on food, energy, vitamins, other topics, 1977 October; 1978 May; 1979; 1980 February 19; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 9)
  - Intermediate Technology: report, article, 1977 Winter-Spring (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 10)
  - Knolls Trident: fact sheet, postcard, 1996 May 02; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 11)
  - Labeling and mental illness: articles by Walter Gove, Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 12)
  - "Latin American Squatter Settlements: A problem and a solution" article by William Mangin, 1967 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 13)
  - Native Americans: youth council annual report fact sheets, Akwesasne Notes journal, Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 14)
  - New York State Emergency Management office: procedures and plans information requests, correspondence, 1985 October 11-1991 February 08 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 15)
  - New York State Emergency Management office: correspondence, press releases, new clippings, 1987 September 01-1989 November 03; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 16)
  - New York State Emergency Management office: correspondence, theoretical population allocation study, 1989 April; 1989 June 30 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 17)
  - New York State Nuclear War Evacuation planning: news clippings, correspondence, 1973 October-1991 January 06; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 18-19)
  - New York State Population Protection Planning: corresponding, reports and summaries, 1988 December 07; 1989 April; 1989 June 30; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 20)
  - Nuclear Disarmament: newspaper clippings, fliers, correspondence, march information training guides, 1982 February 25-1982 May 12; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 21)
  - Nuclear Disarmament, testing, planning: newsletters, 1982 June 07; 1987 Spring; 1988 January; 1989 November; Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 11)
  - Nuclear Disaster Preparedness: correspondence, news clippings, Newsletters, tables and summaries, press releases, 1968 March-1985 March 04 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 22-23)
  - Notes on photographs: diary, Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 24)
  - Nuclear Free Organizing Packet, 1983 February-1983 March; 1983 April; 1984 May 25 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 25)
  - Nuclear Testing: correspondence, news clippings, newsletters, 1976 February 23-1988 February; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 26)
  - Nuclear Testing: news clippings, legislative packets, correspondence, 1982 December 27-1988 May 03; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 27)
  - Nuclear War: News clippings, memos, statement, booklet, 1978 November 10-1983 March 29; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 28)
  - "Plutonium, Proliferation and Policy" article by Victor Gilinsky, 1977 February (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 29)
  - Recycling: News clipping, recycling program list, 1990 February 22; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 30)
  - Seawolf-Kesserling: news clippings, reports, maps, 1972 March 13-1991 September 11 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 31)
  - "Sexual Pleasure: The Surprising Preferences of 100,000 women" article by Robert J. Levin and Amy Levin, 1975 September (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 32)
  - "South End" of Albany Photographs, Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 33)
  - Seneca Army Depot Army tests: press releases, 1990 March 28-1990 June 05; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 34)
  - Silkwood Korea: documentary, news clippings, correspondence, 1983 November 09-1984 January 13; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 35)
  - Strategic Defense Initiative "Star Wars": news clippings, 1984 December 14-1987 Summer; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 36)
  - Social Justice Center: Newsletters, Art Decentralization Grant info,committee, notes, 1988 December-1992 May; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 37)
  - Solar Energy: news clippings, bibliographies, directory, 1976 November-1982 February 28; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 38)
  - Space Funding: graphs, Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 39)
  - "Stop FEMA Curriculum in Schools" pamphlet, correspondence; news clipping, 1982 July 07-1982 November 09; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 40)
  - "Sweat Equity": transcript of the MacNeil/Lehrer Report air date January 1, 1977, Undated (Box 7 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 1)
  - Trees and wood rearrangement: newsletters, 1980 April 26; Undated (Box 7 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 2)
  - United States Invasion of Nicaragua: Defense Monitor newsletter, 1987 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 3)
  - United States nuclear war evacuation planning: notes, magazine, pamphlets, executive summaries, pamphlets, 1979 August 07-1983 November 16; Undated (Box 7 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 4)
  - Watervliet Arsenal: pamphlets, press releases, news clippings, 1986 October-1992 September 17; Undated (Box 7 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 5)
  - "What about the Russians?" article by Thomas J. Watson, Jr., Undated (Box 7 (4-Subject Files for research), Folder 6)